DAN KLEIN: Here's something else
that you can do that's a
variant of local search.
These are called genetic algorithms.
Genetic algorithms are a
kind of local search.
You got, in this case, not one
hypothesis, but you've got a
hypothesis population.
You've got a bunch of hypotheses, and
rather than just locally improving all
of them, which in genetic algorithms
nomenclature is just mere mutation,
you're just mutating these things, they
would say, mutation's not enough.
We've got to do more stuff.
We've got to make it even
more like biology here.
So there's a natural
selection metaphor.
You keep the best end hypotheses at each
step, but you do more than that.
So in addition to just keeping the best
one, then you find pairs and you
do crossover.
Essentially, you mate them.
You take hypotheses, and
you breed hypotheses.
Here's what it looks like.
You have this robot.
Up comes some weird hypothesis robot.
And then, in addition to breeding them,
which is called crossover, you
then mutate them as well, which
is what we were doing all
along in local search.
So it's a little bit more complicated,
but it gets out a few more ideas that
might actually be these kinds
of ridge operators.
So the selection part, that's basically
just like going uphill.
The mutation part, that's basically
looking around in your neighborhood.
Although mutation and selection look
a lot like local search, we have to
think really hard about this
crossover operation.
What does it mean to take two
hypotheses and combine them?
Well, that's really the key.
That might be what gets you
out of a local optimum.
And well, it might look like this.
In n-queens, we might say, well, here's
one hypothesis, and maybe this
hypothesis has basically got the
left half of the board right.
And here's another hypothesis, and maybe
this hypothesis has basically
got the right half of the board right.
And if we mutate them, we're just going
to move one piece at a time and
maybe both of them are pretty far.
But if only we combine them.
We take the left half from one, right
half of the other, we get this new
species of queen solution, and
suddenly we're solved, maybe.
And so here, crossover makes sense
because we've got a way of encoding
the solution where really to have the
prefix of one and the suffix of the
other actually makes sense.
This kind of crossover doesn't make
sense when your solutions aren't
naturally encoded like this, or where a
good left half and a good right half
don't really work together.
And you can imagine some
of those problems here.
It could be that the left half is
perfectly good, and the right have is
perfectly good, but they both use the
bottom of the board, and then the
crossover would not be effective.
One more thing to say about these
variance of local search.
They're very powerful in practice, but
they're also pretty easy to misuse.
So for things like genetic algorithms,
they're very often misapplied.